Hello and welcome back.
Today we are going to look at a business logic vulnerability that cannot be detected by
a traditional security scanners.
The vulnerability is called Confused Deputy and it falls under the always top 10 category
of a broken authorization.
In my opinion any company offers remote MCP server might have confused debutability if
they give their MCP server a broad access to a back-end services.
Before we dive into details and the lab, I want to share with you a real-world incident
that happened in remote MCP with a broken authorization happened to Asana in 2025.
I want to read a couple of lines from Sans in Newsletter.
Asana has fixed a vulnerability in their implementation of model context protocol artificial
intelligence integration protocol that could have been exploited to see data belonging
to other organizations.
While there is no technical write-up published about this incident, we can read from those
lines or we can get from those lines that the root cause was a broken authorization in
the remote MCP server.
In multi-tenant services allowing user A to access data of user B in another organizations,
this is catastrophic.
Let's try to understand why could this happen in the first place.
So when the developers want to introduce an integrate remote MCP server with their back-end
services, they already have API's any place to access their services by customers.
Let's assume those API's have a proper authorization checks, something like validating
authorization token, the token scope, enforcing access control etc.
So everything could be secure from the API perspective that is served by the back-end.
However, now they want to introduce AI capabilities to their platform to better serve their
customers and become more competitive.
The MCP server in this case is going to be the bridge between the customers AI model and
the data that lives in the back-end services.
So here's the problem.
The MCP server will accept requests from all customers and all users.
And somehow it needs a way to access the data on behalf of those users.
In order to process the requests.
So how can the MCP server ensure that user A can only access data belonging to a user A
and not that I belong to a user B?
So to solve this problem, developers usually take one of those two approaches.
Option one, they gave the MCP server itself an access token with wide permissions and
the MCP server can use it's own access token to access any data using the existing public
API endpoints provided by the back-end services.
Option B, they could build a dedicated internal endpoint that the MCP server can use again
to access any user's data.
Both approaches are fundamentally flawed because they completely ignore the risk of someone
abusing the MCP server itself to access data of other users.
In other words, if user A asks the MCP server to get data of user B, then the MCP server
can technically do that because it has a broad access.
In my opinion, the secure implementation would be instead of rebuilding the authorization,
verification logic in the MCP server or giving the MCP server broad access with this
wide permission access token.
Developers should build the MCP to require the user to pass its own access token to the
MCP first and then the MCP would use the user's access token to the back-end API instead
of using a wide permission access token created for the MCP server itself.
And by doing so, you could reuse the authorization verification that you already have
at the back-end services level.
In the next lecture, we will see this vulnerability in action, so I hope that this lecture
has been informative for you and I will see you in the next one.
Thanks for watching.